<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE Articles
    PUBLIC "-//Medstract//DTD XML Medstract annotations//EN//XML"
    "http://www.cs.brandeis.edu/~steele/medstract/Medstract.dtd">
<Articles><Article>
<T>Immunohistochemical localization of <Entity id="5" Type="Protein">FAP-1</Entity>, an <InhibitRelation id="7" Inhibitor="5"  Inhibitee="6" Kind="Undetermined">inhibitor of</InhibitRelation> <Entity id="6" Type="cellular process">Fas-mediated apoptosis</Entity>, in normal and neoplastic human tissues</T>
<A>S. H. Lee, M. S. Shin, W. S. Park, S. Y. Kim, H. S. Kim, J. H. Lee, S. Y. Han, H. K. Lee, J. Y. Park, R. R. Oh, J. J. Jang, J. Y. Lee and N. J. Yoo</A>
<J>Apmis</J>
<V>107</V>
<P>1101-8</P>
<Y>1999</Y>
<Ab><Entity id="1" Type="Protein">Fas</Entity>, a death receptor, is widely expressed in human tissue, but <Entity id="3" Type="molecular process"><Entity id="2" Antecedent="1">its</Entity> expression</Entity>, although a prerequisite for the induction of apoptosis, does not predict <Entity id="5" Type="physiological process"><Entity id="4" Antecedent="2">its</Entity> biological function</Entity>. To understand the mechanisms of Fas resistance in human tissues in vivo, we performed immunohistochemistry using an antibody against <Entity id="8" Type="Protein">Fas-associated phosphatase-1 </Entity>(<Entity id="9" Aliasof="8">FAP-1</Entity>), <Entity id="10" Antecedent="9">which </Entity>interacts with the cytosolic domain of Fas and <InhibitRelation id="12" Inhibitor="10"  Inhibitee="11" Kind="Undetermined">inhibits </InhibitRelation><Entity id="11" Type="cellular process">Fas-mediated apoptosis</Entity>. In normal human tissues, FAP-1 immunostaining was easily detected, for example, in renal tubules, skeletal muscle, myocardiocytes, pituitary gland, parathyroid gland, pancreatic islets, hepatocytes, testicular germ cells, prostatic glands, neurons, epithelium of fallopian tube, endometrial glands, trophoblasts, bronchial epithelial cells, and some types of gastrointestinal epithelial cells. In 123 (78%) of 158 cancers of various origins, including breast carcinomas, stomach carcinomas, colon carcinomas, lung carcinomas and several types of sarcomas, variable intensities of FAP-1 expression were evident. Taken together, these findings demonstrated that FAP-1 is widely expressed in normal human tissues and partly overlapped with Fas expression described in earlier reports, suggesting that FAP-1 may have an important role in the regulation of apoptosis in vivo. In addition, FAP-1 expression in cancers suggests that many cancers may be resistant to Fas-mediated apoptosis through the action of FAP-1 in vivo.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Paracrine regulation of ovarian cancer by endothelin</T>
<A>S. Moraitis, W. R. Miller, J. F. Smyth and S. P. Langdon</A>
<J>Eur J Cancer</J>
<V>35</V>
<P>1381-7</P>
<Y>1999</Y>
<Ab>Previous studies have demonstrated that <Entity id="6" Type="Protein"><Entity id="13" Type="Protein">endothelin </Entity>(<Entity id="14" Aliasof="13">ET</Entity>) isoforms</Entity> (<Entity id="7" Acronym="6">ET-1, ET-2 and ET-3</Entity>) can act in an autocrine manner in ovarian cancer while in breast cancer <Entity id="8" Antecedent="6">their</Entity> role has been proposed to be that of a paracrine mitogen. To explore the possibility that <Entity id="9" Type="Protein">endothelin isoforms</Entity> might function not only as autocrine regulators but also as paracrine mitogens in ovarian cancers, we investigated <Entity id="10" Antecedent="9">their</Entity> effects on the growth of ovarian fibroblasts derived from ovarian carcinomas, the interaction between ovarian carcinoma and fibroblast cells and the location of the isoform expression in primary ovarian tumours. ET-1, ET-2 and ET-3 stimulated the growth of three ovarian fibroblast cell lines at concentrations ranging from 10(-12) M to 10(-7) M. <InhibitRelation id="18" Inhibitor="16, 17"  Inhibitee="15" Kind="Undetermined">Inhibition of</InhibitRelation> <Entity id="15" Type="molecular process">125I-ET binding</Entity> by the <Entity id="16" Type="small molecule"><Entity id="11" Type="Protein">ETA receptor</Entity> antagonist BQ123</Entity> and the <Entity id="17" Type="small molecule"><Entity id="12" Type="Protein">ETB receptor</Entity> antagonist BQ788</Entity> suggested the presence of both types of ET receptors in fibroblast cells. In the absence of ET-1, neither <Entity id="19" Type="small molecule">BQ 123</Entity> nor <Entity id="20" Type="small molecule">BQ 788</Entity> <InhibitRelation id="22" Inhibitor="19, 20"  Inhibitee="21" Kind="Undetermined">inhibited </InhibitRelation><Entity id="21" Type="cellular process">growth</Entity>. However, <Entity id="23" Antecedent="19, 20">both antagonists</Entity> <InhibitRelation id="25" Inhibitor="23"  Inhibitee="24" Kind="Undetermined">inhibited </InhibitRelation><Entity id="24" Type="cellular process">ET-1 stimulated growth</Entity> suggesting the involvement of <Entity id="13" Antecedent="11, 12">both receptor types</Entity> in ET-1 growth regulation. In contrast to carcinoma cells which secrete measurable levels of ET-1, fibroblast cell lines did not secrete detectable protein. Co-culture experiments (using porous membrane insert wells) of <Entity id="40" Type="cell type">fibroblasts</Entity> with <Entity id="41" Type="cell type">carcinoma cells</Entity> demonstrated that growth of <Entity id="42" Antecedent="40, 41">both populations of cells</Entity> was increased compared with <Entity id="43" Antecedent="40, 41">either</Entity> grown in isolation. In this system, <Entity id="26" Type="cellular process">growth of the fibroblast cell line</Entity> <InhibitRelation id="29" Inhibitor="27, 28"  Inhibitee="26" Kind="Undetermined">was partially inhibited by</InhibitRelation> both <Entity id="27" Type="small molecule">BQ123 </Entity>and <Entity id="28" Type="small molecule">BQ788</Entity>, whilst <Entity id="30" Type="cellular process">growth of the PE014 carcinoma cell line</Entity> <InhibitRelation id="32" Inhibitor="31"  Inhibitee="30" Kind="Undetermined">was inhibited by</InhibitRelation> only <Entity id="31" Type="small molecule">BQ123</Entity>. RT-PCR measurements detected the presence of the ETA receptor subtype in 10/10 primary ovarian cancers but the presence of ETB receptor in only 6/10 cancers. Using specific antibodies, ET-1 was found in 11/15, ET-2 in 5 of 7 and ET-3 in 5/7 primary ovarian cancers predominantly in the epithelial cells but with some stromal expression. These data indicate that the ET isoforms may stimulate growth of the fibroblast population within an ovarian cancer in addition to stimulating the epithelial cells and since the ETs are expressed in the majority of ovarian cancers, this paracrine effect may contribute to the overall growth of the tumour.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Pharmacological characterization of receptor-mediated Ca2+ entry in endothelin-1-induced catecholamine release from cultured bovine adrenal chromaffin cells</T>
<A>K. Lee, H. Morita, Y. Iwamuro, X. F. Zhang, Y. Okamoto, T. Nakagawa, H. Hasegawa, H. Furutani, S. Miwa and T. Masaki</A>
<J>Naunyn Schmiedebergs Arch Pharmacol</J>
<V>360</V>
<P>616-22</P>
<Y>1999</Y>
<Ab>To clarify the mechanism for the endothelin-1 (ET-1)-induced release of catecholamines from the adrenal gland, we examined the effects of removal of extracellular Ca2+, blockers of L-, N-, P- and Q-types of voltage-operated Ca2+ channels (VOCC) such as nifedipine (L-type), omega-conotoxin GVIA (N-type), omega-agatoxin IVA (P-type) and omega-conotoxin MVIIC (Q-type) and blockers of voltage-independent Ca2+ entry channel such as SKF 96365 and LOE 908 on release of catecholamines, the cytosolic free Ca2+ concentration ([Ca2+]i), and 45Ca2+ uptake in cultured bovine adrenal chromaffin cells. ET-1 but not ET-3 induced <Entity id="39" Type="cellular process">increases in release of catecholamines</Entity>, [Ca2+]i, and 45Ca2+ uptake. The responses to ET-1 were abolished by the antagonist for ET(A) receptors, BQ-123, but not by the antagonist for ET(B) receptors, BQ-788, and they were abolished by removal of extracellular Ca2+. <Entity id="40" Antecedent="39">The increases</Entity> <InhibitRelation id="42" Inhibitor="41"  Inhibitee="40" Kind="Undetermined">were only partially inhibited</InhibitRelation> (to about 65% of control) by <Entity id="41" Type="small molecule">nifedipine</Entity> but unaffected by any of the omega-toxins. The <Entity id="43" Type="cellular process">nifedipine-resistant increase</Entity> <InhibitRelation id="45" Inhibitor="44"  Inhibitee="43" Kind="Undetermined">was inhibited by</InhibitRelation> <Entity id="44" Type="small molecule">SKF 96365</Entity> (to about 40%) and abolished by LOE 908 alone. These results indicate that ET-1 augments the release of catecholamines from adrenal chromaffin cells through ET(A) receptors, by activating two types of Ca2+ entry channels in addition to L-type VOCC: one (nonselective cation channel-1; NSCC-1) is sensitive to LOE 908 but resistant to SKF 96365, whereas the other (NSCC-2) is sensitive to both LOE 908 and SK&amp;F 96365.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Metabolism-based <Entity id="29" Type="small molecule">polycyclic aromatic acetylene</Entity> <InhibitRelation id="31" Inhibitor="29"  Inhibitee="30" Kind="Undetermined">inhibition of</InhibitRelation> <Entity id="30" Type="Protein">CYP1B1</Entity> in 10T1/2 cells potentiates aryl hydrocarbon receptor activity</T>
<A>D. L. Alexander, L. Zhang, M. Foroozesh, W. L. Alworth and C. R. Jefcoate</A>
<J>Toxicol Appl Pharmacol</J>
<V>161</V>
<P>123-39</P>
<Y>1999</Y>
<Ab>We have used polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon (PAH) alkyne metabolism-based <InhibitRelation id="22" Inhibitor="29"  Inhibitee="30" Kind="Undetermined">inhibitors </InhibitRelation>
to test whether CYP1B1 metabolism is linked to aryl hydrocarbon receptor (AhR) activation in <Entity id="51" Type="cell type">mouse embryo fibroblasts (MEF)</Entity>. <Entity id="8" Type="small molecule">1-ethynylpyrene</Entity> (<Entity id="9" Aliasof="8">1EP</Entity>) selectively inactivated CYP1B1 <Entity id="5" Type="small molecule">dimethylbenzanthracene </Entity>(<Entity id="6" Aliasof="5">DMBA</Entity>) metabolism in <Entity id="52" Instanceof="51">C3H10T1/2 MEFs</Entity>; whereas <Entity id="1" Type="small molecule">1-(1-propynyl)pyrene </Entity>(<Entity id="2" Aliasof="1">1PP</Entity>) preferentially <InhibitRelation id="4" Inhibitor="1"  Inhibitee="3" Kind="Undetermined">inhibited </InhibitRelation><Entity id="3" Type="Protein">CYP1A1 activity</Entity> in <Entity id="50" Type="cell type">Hepa-1c1c7 mouse hepatoma cells (Hepa)</Entity>. In <Entity id="21" Antecedent="52, 50">each cell type</Entity> >90% <InhibitRelation id="11" Inhibitor="10"  Inhibitee="7" Kind="Undetermined">inhibition of</InhibitRelation> <Entity id="7" Type="molecular process">DMBA metabolism</Entity> after 1 h treatment with <Entity id="10" Antecedent="8, 1">each inhibitor</Entity> (0.1 microM) was progressively reversed and then increased to levels seen with 2,3,7,8-tetrachlorodibenzo-p-dioxin (TCDD) induction (fourfold stimulation). It was found that 0.1 microM 1EP and 1PP maximally induce <Entity id="14" Type="gene">CYP1B1 and CYP1A1 mRNA</Entity> levels in 10T1/2 and Hepa cells, respectively, after 6 h. <Entity id="12" Type="small molecule">1-Ethylpyrene </Entity>(<Entity id="13" Aliasof="12">EtP</Entity>), which lacks the activatable acetylene moiety, was far less effective as <InhibitRelation id="15" Inhibitor="12"  Inhibitee="14" Kind="Undetermined">an inhibitor</InhibitRelation> and as an inducer. AhR activation is essential for 1EP induction as evidenced by the use of AhR antagonists and AhR-deficient MEFs and absence of induction following <InhibitRelation id="19" Inhibitor="17"  Inhibitee="16" Kind="Undetermined">inhibition of</InhibitRelation> <Entity id="16" Type="molecular process">DMBA metabolism</Entity> with <Entity id="17" Type="small molecule">carbon monoxide</Entity> (<Entity id="18" Aliasof="17">CO</Entity>). <InhibitRelation id="21" Inhibitor="unspecified"  Inhibitee="20" Kind="Undetermined">Inhibition of</InhibitRelation> <Entity id="20" Type="Protein">CYP1B1 </Entity>was linked to enhanced AhR activation even at early stages prior to significant ligand depletion. 1EP and EtP were similarly effective in stimulating AhR nuclear translocation, though 5-10 times slower compared with TCDD, and produced no significant down-regulation of the AhR. TCDD activated AhR/Arnt complex formation with an oligonucleotide xenobiotic response element far more extensively than 1EP or EtP, even at concentrations of 1EP that increased CYP1B1 mRNA to similar levels. CO did not influence these responses to EtP, event hough CO treatment potentiated EtP induction of CYP1B1 mRNA. These differences suggest a fundamental difference between PAH/AhR and TCDD/AhR complexes where CYP1B1 metabolic activity regulates the potency, rather than the formation of the AhR/Arnt complex. Copyright 1999 Academic Press.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Endothelin-1 activates p38 mitogen-activated protein kinase via endothelin-A receptor in rat myocardial cells</T>
<A>T. Ueyama, S. Kawashima, T. Sakoda, Y. Rikitake, T. Ishida, M. Kawai, M. Namiki and M. Yokoyama</A>
<J>Mol Cell Biochem</J>
<V>199</V>
<P>119-24</P>
<Y>1999</Y>
<Ab>In myocardial cells (MCs), endothelin-1 (ET-1) exerts various effects such as hypertrophy, and causes cellular injury. Long-term treatment with an <Entity id="9" Type="Protein">endothelin-A</Entity> (<Entity id="10" Aliasof="9">ET(A)</Entity>) receptor antagonist improves the survival of rats with heart failure, suggesting that myocardial endothelin system contributes to the progression of heart failure. <Entity id="17" Type="Protein">p38 mitogen-activated kinase</Entity> (<Entity id="18" Aliasof="17">MAPK</Entity>) is a member of the MAPK family and activated by several forms of environmental stresses. We show here the effect of ET-1 on p38 MAPK activation and the role of ET-1-activated p38 MAPK on morphological changes in MCs. ET-1-stimulated <Entity id="8" Type="molecular process">p38 MAPK phosphorylation</Entity> was detectable within 2 min and maximal at 5 min and was concentration dependent. The maximum effect was obtained at 10 nM. An <Entity id="11" Type="small molecule">ET(A) receptor antagonist</Entity>, <Entity id="12" Aliasof="11">BQ-123</Entity>, but not an <Entity id="14" Type="small molecule">endothelin-B receptor antagonist</Entity>, <Entity id="15" Aliasof="14">BQ-788</Entity>, <InhibitRelation id="16" Inhibitor="11,12, not 14, not 15"  Inhibitee="" Kind="Undetermined">inhibited </InhibitRelation>
<Entity id="13" Antecedent="8">these reactions</Entity>. A <Entity id="19" Type="small molecule">p38 MAPK inhibitor</Entity>, <Entity id="20" Aliasof="19">SB203580</Entity>, <InhibitRelation id="22" Inhibitor="not 19, not 20"  Inhibitee="21" Kind="Undetermined">failed to inhibit</InhibitRelation> the <Entity id="21" Type="cellular process">morphological changes associated with ET-1-induced myocardial cell hypertrophy</Entity>. These results indicate that p38 MAPK is activated by ET-1 but does not contribute to the development of ET-1-induced myocardial cell hypertrophy.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Endothelin receptors and calcium translocation pathways in human airways</T>
<A>D. W. Hay, M. A. Luttmann, R. M. Muccitelli and R. G. Goldie</A>
<J>Naunyn Schmiedebergs Arch Pharmacol</J>
<V>359</V>
<P>404-10</P>
<Y>1999</Y>     
<Ab>Tension and <Entity id="17" Type="small molecule">phosphatidyl inositol</Entity> (<Entity id="18" Aliasof="17">PI</Entity>) turnover experiments were conducted to investigate the receptors and signal transduction pathways responsible for <Entity id="2" Type="cellular process">contractions elicited by <Entity id="12" Type="Protein">endothelin </Entity>(<Entity id="13" Aliasof="12">ET</Entity>) ligands in human bronchus</Entity>. <Entity id="51" Type="small molecule">Nicardipine </Entity>(1 microM), the <Entity id="52" Type="Protein">L-type calcium channel</Entity> <InhibitRelation id="53" Inhibitor="51"  Inhibitee="52" Kind="Undetermined">inhibitor</InhibitRelation>, or incubation in <Entity id="1" Type="undetermined">Ca2+-free medium</Entity>, produced <InhibitRelation id="4" Inhibitor="1"  Inhibitee="3" Kind="Undetermined">marked inhibition</InhibitRelation> of <Entity id="3" Antecedent="2">contractions</Entity> to the ET(B) receptor-selective agonist, sarafotoxin S6c, and especially <Entity id="30" Antecedent="3">those</Entity> induced by KCl. In contrast, Ca2+-free medium was without appreciable effect against contraction produced by endothelin-1 (ET-1), the non-selective ET(A) and ET(B) receptor agonist. In Ca2+-free medium, <Entity id="5" Type="small molecule">ryanodine </Entity>(10 microM), which <InhibitRelation id="7" Inhibitor="5"  Inhibitee="6" Kind="Undetermined">inhibits </InhibitRelation><Entity id="6" Type="molecular process">intracellular calcium mobilization</Entity>, reduced sarafotoxin S6c- and ET-1-induced responses, but was without effect on responses to KCl. Similarly, <Entity id="8" Type="small molecule">nickel chloride </Entity>(Ni2+; 1 mM) caused <InhibitRelation id="10" Inhibitor="8"  Inhibitee="9, not 11" Kind="Undetermined">marked inhibition</InhibitRelation> of <Entity id="9" Type="cellular process">contractions induced by sarafotoxin S6c or ET-1</Entity>, but had no significant effect on <Entity id="11" Type="undetermined">KCI concentration-response curves</Entity>. The mixed <Entity id="14" Type="small molecule">ET(A)/ET(B) receptor antagonist</Entity> <Entity id="25" Aliasof="14">SB 209670</Entity> (3 microM) <InhibitRelation id="16" Inhibitor="14"  Inhibitee="15" Kind="Undetermined">inhibited </InhibitRelation><Entity id="15" Type="cellular process">responses to sarafotoxin S6c and ET-1</Entity> such that concentration-response curves were shifted rightward, at the 30% maximum response level, by 10.0- and 3.8-fold, respectively, whereas <Entity id="23" Type="small molecule">BQ-123</Entity> (3 microM), the <Entity id="24" Aliasof="23">ET(A) receptor antagonist</Entity>, was without effect on response induced by either agonist. ET-1 (1 nM-0.3 microM) caused a concentration-dependent stimulation of PI turnover, whereas sarafotoxin S6c (0.3 nM-0.1 microM) induced only small and variable increases, except at the highest concentration. <Entity id="19" Type="molecular process">The increase in PI turnover evoked by ET-1</Entity> was <InhibitRelation id="22" Inhibitor="19"  Inhibitee="20, 21" Kind="Undetermined">inhibited by</InhibitRelation> <Entity id="20" Type="small molecule">SB 209670</Entity> (3 microM), and also by <Entity id="21" Type="small molecule">BQ-123</Entity> (3 microM). This is consistent with linkage of ET(A) receptors to activation of inositol phosphate generation in human bronchial smooth muscle cells. Collectively, the data suggest that differences exist in the relative contributions of intracellular and extracellular Ca2+ mobilization mechanisms elicited by ET(A) and ET(B) receptor activation. Thus, sarafotoxin S6c-induced, <Entity id="34" Type="cellular process">ET(B) receptor-mediated contraction in human bronchial smooth muscle</Entity> appears to be dependent, in part, upon extracellular Ca2+, although a significant component of <Entity id="25" Antecedent="34">the response</Entity>
 was also mediated by intracellular Ca2+ release, including from ryanodine-sensitive stores. ET(A) receptor-mediated contraction of human airway smooth muscle was activated largely via the release of intracellular Ca2+.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Carbon-11 epidepride: a suitable radioligand for PET investigation of striatal and extrastriatal dopamine D2 receptors</T>
<A>O. Langer, C. Halldin, F. Dolle, C. G. Swahn, H. Olsson, P. Karlsson, H. Hall, J. Sandell, C. Lundkvist, F. Vaufrey, C. Loc'h, C. Crouzel, B. Maziere and L. Farde</A>
<J>Nucl Med Biol</J>
<V>26</V>
<P>509-18</P>
<Y>1999</Y>
<Ab>Epidepride [(S)-(-)-N-([1-ethyl-2-pyrrolidinyl]methyl)-5-iodo-2,3-dimethoxybenza mide] binds with a picomolar affinity (Ki = 24 pM) to the dopamine D2 receptor. Iodine-123-labeled epidepride has been used previously to study striatal and extrastriatal dopamine D2 receptors with single photon emission computed tomography (SPECT). Our aim was to label epidepride with carbon-11 for comparative quantitative studies between positron emission tomography (PET) and SPECT. Epidepride was synthesized from its bromo-analogue FLB 457 via the corresponding trimethyl-tin derivative. In an alternative synthetic pathway, the corresponding substituted benzoic acid was reacted with the optically pure aminomethylpyrrolidine-derivative. Demethylation of epidepride gave the desmethyl-derivative, which was reacted with [11C]methyl triflate. Total radiochemical yield was 40-50% within a total synthesis time of 30 min. The specific radioactivity at the end of synthesis was 37-111 GBq/micromol (1,000-3,000 Ci/mmol). Human postmortem whole-hemisphere autoradiography demonstrated dense <Entity id="37" Type="molecular process">binding in the caudate putamen</Entity>, and also in extrastriatal areas such as the thalamus and the neocortex. <Entity id="38" Antecedent="37">The binding </Entity>was <InhibitRelation id="40" Inhibitor="38"  Inhibitee="39" Kind="Undetermined">inhibited </InhibitRelation>by unlabeled <Entity id="39" Type="small molecule">raclopride</Entity>. PET studies in a cynomolgus monkey demonstrated high uptake in the striatum and in several extrastriatal regions. At 90 min after injection, uptake in the striatum, thalamus and neocortex was about 11, 4, and 2 times higher than in the cerebellum, respectively. Pretreatment experiment with unlabeled <Entity id="41" Type="small molecule">raclopride </Entity>(1 mg/kg) <InhibitRelation id="43" Inhibitor="41"  Inhibitee="42" Kind="Undetermined">inhibited 50-70%</InhibitRelation> of <Entity id="42" Type="molecular process">[11C]epidepride binding</Entity>. The fraction of unchanged [11C]epidepride in monkey plasma determined by a gradient high performance liquid chromatography (HPLC) method was about 30% of the total radioactivity at 30 min after injection of [11C]epidepride. The availability of [11C]epidepride allows the PET-verification of the data obtained from quantitation studies with SPECT.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>p27 expression as a prognostic factor of breast cancer in Taiwan</T>
<A>J. S. Chu, C. S. Huang and K. J. Chang</A>
<J>Cancer Lett</J>
<V>141</V>
<P>123-30</P>
<Y>1999</Y>
<Ab><Entity id="72" Type="Protein">p27Kip1</Entity> is a member of the <Entity id="69" Type="Protein">Cip/Kip</Entity> family of <Entity id="70" Type="Protein">cyclin-dependent kinase </Entity><InhibitRelation id="71" Inhibitor="69"  Inhibitee="70" Kind="Undetermined">inhibitors</InhibitRelation>. <Entity id="73" Antecedent="72">It </Entity>binds to a variety of cyclin/CDK complexes, <InhibitRelation id="75" Inhibitor="73"  Inhibitee="74" Kind="Undetermined">inhibits </InhibitRelation><Entity id="74" Type="Protein">kinase activity</Entity>, and blocks the cell cycle. Absent or reduced p27 expression has been shown to be a significant predictor of poor survival in breast, colorectal, prostate, non-small cell lung and esophagus carcinomas. An immunohistochemical assay was performed on 169 patients with primary breast cancers to evaluate the biologic significance of p27 expression. Decreased p27 expression was significantly associated with high grade (P = 0.00025), negative estrogen receptor (P = 0.00004), and negative progesterone receptor (P = 0.0038) breast cancers. Univariate analysis reveals that p27 expression inversely correlated significantly with overall survival (P = 0.0001). By multivariate analysis, p27 predicted the overall survival independently (P = 0.0096). Our study indicates that p27 expression is an independent prognostic marker of breast cancer in Taiwan.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Developmental conversion of inotropism by endothelin I and angiotensin II from positive to negative in mice</T>
<A>T. Sekine, H. Kusano, K. Nishimaru, Y. Tanaka, H. Tanaka and K. Shigenobu</A>
<J>Eur J Pharmacol</J>
<V>374</V>
<P>411-5</P>
<Y>1999</Y>
<Ab><Entity id="95" Type="physiological process">Inotropic effects</Entity> on isolated neonatal and adult mouse myocardium of endothelin I and angiotensin II were examined. Endothelin I produced a sustained <Entity id="26" Instanceof="95">positive inotropic response in the neonate</Entity> but a sustained <Entity id="27" Instanceof="95">negative response in the adult</Entity>. <Entity id="96" Antecedent="26, 27">Both</Entity> were concentration-dependent and were <InhibitRelation id="99" Inhibitor="97"  Inhibitee="96" Kind="Undetermined">inhibited</InhibitRelation> by the <Entity id="97" Type="small molecule">endothelin ETA receptor antagonist, BQ-123</Entity> <Entity id="98" Aliasof="97">(Cyclo(D-a-aspartyl-L-prolyl-D-valyl-L-leucyl-D-tryptophyl))</Entity>. Angiotensin II produced a sustained <Entity id="28" Instanceof="95">positive inotropic response in the neonate</Entity> while a sustained <Entity id="29" Instanceof="95">negative response in the adult</Entity>. <Entity id="100" Antecedent="28, 29">Both</Entity> were concentration-dependent and were <InhibitRelation id="103" Inhibitor="101"  Inhibitee="100" Kind="Undetermined">inhibited </InhibitRelation>by the <Entity id="101" Type="small molecule">angiotensin AT1 receptor antagonist, YM358</Entity> (<Entity id="102" Aliasof="101">2,7-diethyl-5-((2'-(1 H-tetrazol-5-yl)biphenyl-4-yl)methyl-5H-pyrazolo(1,5-b)(1,2,4)tria zole potassium salt monohydrate)</Entity>. These results indicate that inotropic responses of the mouse heart to cardioactive peptides are unique among experimental animal species and may be reversed during development.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>The <Entity id="30" Type="Protein">30-kD subunit of mammalian cleavage and polyadenylation specificity factor</Entity> and <Entity id="32" Type="Protein"><Entity id="31" Antecedent="30">its</Entity> yeast homolog</Entity> are RNA-binding zinc finger proteins</T>
<A>S. M. Barabino, W. Hubner, A. Jenny, L. Minvielle-Sebastia and W. Keller</A>
<J>Genes Dev</J>
<V>11</V>
<P>1703-16.</P>
<Y>1997</Y>
<Ab><Entity id="1" Type="Protein">Cleavage and polyadenylation specificity factor</Entity> (<Entity id="2" Acronym="1">CPSF</Entity>), a key component of the mammalian RNA 3'-end processing machinery, consists of four subunits of 160, 100, 73, and 30 kD. Here we report the isolation and characterization of a cDNA encoding the <Entity id="3" Type="Protein">30-kD polypeptide</Entity>. Antibodies raised against <Entity id="4" Antecedent="3">this protein</Entity> inhibit cleavage and polyadenylation and <ComplexRelation id="6" Complexor="4"  Complexee="5" Kind="Undetermined">coimmunoprecipitate </ComplexRelation>the other <Entity id="5" Type="Protein">CPSF subunits</Entity>. <Entity id="33" Antecedent="4">The protein sequence</Entity> contains five C3H-zinc-finger repeats and a putative RNA-binding zinc knuckle motif at the carboxyl terminus. Consistent with this observation, the in vitro translated <Entity id="8" Type="Protein">30-kD protein</Entity> <ComplexRelation id="9" Complexor="8"  Complexee="7" Kind="Undetermined">binds </ComplexRelation><Entity id="7" Type="RNA">RNA polymers</Entity> with a distinct preference for poly(U). In addition, an <Entity id="12" Type="gene">essential S. cerevisiae gene</Entity>, <Entity id="13" Aliasof="12">YTH1</Entity>, was cloned which is 40% identical to CPSF 30K at the protein level. Extracts prepared from a conditional yth1 mutant have normal cleavage activity, but fail to polyadenylate the upstream cleavage product. Efficient polyadenylation activity can be restored by the addition of <Entity id="10" Type="Protein">purified polyadenylation factor I</Entity> (<Entity id="11" Acronym="10">PF I</Entity>). We demonstrate that <Entity id="16" Type="Protein">Yth1p </Entity>is a <ComplexRelation id="20" Complexor="16"  Complexee="19" Kind="Undetermined">component of</ComplexRelation> <Entity id="19" Type="Protein">PF I</Entity> that <ComplexRelation id="18" Complexor="16"  Complexee="14" Kind="Undetermined">interacts in vivo and in vitro with</ComplexRelation> <Entity id="14" Type="Protein">Fip1p</Entity>, a known <Entity id="21" Type="Protein">PF I</Entity> <ComplexRelation id="22" Complexor="14"  Complexee="21" Kind="Undetermined">subunit</ComplexRelation>.
</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>ATP stimulation of <Entity id="35" Type="molecular process">Na+/Ca2+ exchange in cardiac sarcolemmal vesicles</Entity></T>
<A>G. Berberian, C. Hidalgo, R. DiPolo and L. Beauge</A>
<J>Am J Physiol</J>
<V>274</V>
<P>C724-33.</P>
<Y>1998</Y>
<Ab>In cardiac sarcolemmal vesicles, MgATP stimulates <Entity id="36" Antecedent="35">Na+/Ca2+ exchange</Entity> with the following characteristics: 1) increases 10-fold the apparent affinity for cytosolic Ca2+; 2) a Michaelis constant for ATP of approximately 500 microM; 3) requires micromolar vanadate while millimolar concentrations are inhibitory; 4) not observed in the presence of 20 microM eosin alone but reinstated when vanadate is added; 5) mimicked by adenosine 5'-O-(3-thiotriphosphate), without the need for vanadate, but not by beta,gamma-methyleneadenosine 5'-triphosphate; and 6) not affected by unspecific protein alkaline phosphatase but abolished by a phosphatidylinositol-specific phospholipase C (PI-PLC). The PI-PLC effect is counteracted by phosphatidylinositol. In addition, in the absence of ATP, <Entity id="59" Type="small molecule">L-alpha-phosphatidylinositol 4,5-bisphosphate</Entity> (<Entity id="60" Acronym="59">PIP2</Entity>) was able to stimulate <Entity id="37" Antecedent="35">the exchanger activity in vesicles</Entity> pretreated with PI-PLC. This MgATP stimulation is not related to phosphorylation of the carrier, whereas phosphorylation appeared in the <Entity id="61" Type="small molecule">phosphoinositides</Entity>, mainly <Entity id="62" Instanceof="61">PIP2</Entity>, that <ComplexRelation id="64" Complexor="62"  Complexee="63" Kind="Undetermined">coimmunoprecipitate with</ComplexRelation> <Entity id="63" Antecedent="37">the exchanger</Entity>. Vesicles incubated with MgATP and no Ca2+ show a marked synthesis of L-alpha-phosphatidylinositol 4-monophosphate (PIP) with little production of PIP2; in the presence of 1 microM Ca2+, the net synthesis of PIP is smaller, whereas that of PIP2 increases ninefold. These results indicate that PIP2 is involved in the MgATP stimulation of the <Entity id="38" Antecedent="63">cardiac Na+/Ca2+ exchanger</Entity> through a fast phosphorylation chain: a Ca(2+)-independent PIP formation followed by a Ca(2+)-dependent synthesis of PIP2.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Effects of purified recombinant neural and muscle agrin on skeletal muscle fibers in vivo</T>
<A>G. Bezakova, J. P. Helm, M. Francolini and T. Lomo</A>
<J>J Cell Biol</J>
<V>153</V>
<P>1441-52.</P>
<Y>2001</Y>
<Ab>Aggregation of acetylcholine receptors (AChRs) in muscle fibers by nerve-derived agrin plays a key role in the formation of neuromuscular junctions. So far, the effects of agrin on muscle fibers have been studied in culture systems, transgenic animals, and in animals injected with agrin--cDNA constructs. We have applied purified recombinant chick neural and muscle agrin to rat soleus muscle in vivo and obtained the following results. Both <Entity id="1" Type="Protein">neural and muscle agrin</Entity> <ComplexRelation id="3" Complexor="1"  Complexee="2" Kind="Undetermined">bind </ComplexRelation>uniformly to the surface of innervated and denervated <Entity id="2" Type="cell type">muscle fibers</Entity> along <Entity id="39" Antecedent="2">their</Entity> entire length. Neural agrin causes a dose-dependent appearance of AChR aggregates, which persist >or = 7 wk after a single application. Muscle agrin does not cluster AChRs and at 10 times the concentration of neural agrin does not reduce binding or AChR-aggregating activity of neural agrin. Electrical muscle activity affects the stability of <Entity id="4" Type="Protein">agrin</Entity> <ComplexRelation id="6" Complexor="4"  Complexee="5" Kind="Undetermined">binding </ComplexRelation>and the number, size, and spatial distribution of the <Entity id="5" Type="small molecule">neural agrin--induced AChR aggregates</Entity>. Injected <Entity id="7" Type="Protein">agrin</Entity> is recovered from the muscles together with <Entity id="8" Type="Protein">laminin</Entity> and <Entity id="9" Antecedent="7, 8">both proteins</Entity> <ComplexRelation id="10" Complexor="7, 8"  Complexee="7, 8" Kind="Undetermined">coimmunoprecipitate</ComplexRelation>, indicating that <Entity id="11" Type="Protein">agrin</Entity> <ComplexRelation id="13" Complexor="11"  Complexee="12" Kind="Undetermined">binds to</ComplexRelation> <Entity id="12" Type="Protein">laminin</Entity> in vivo. Thus, the present approach provides a novel, simple, and efficient method for studying the effects of agrin on muscle under controlled conditions in vivo.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T><Entity id="16" Instanceof="15">Neurabin</Entity> is a <Entity id="15" Type="Protein">synaptic protein</Entity> <ComplexRelation id="19" Complexor="16"  Complexee="17, 18" Kind="Undetermined">linking</ComplexRelation> <Entity id="17" Type="Protein">p70 S6 kinase</Entity> and the <Entity id="18" Type="cytoskeleton">neuronal cytoskeleton</Entity></T>
<A>P. E. Burnett, S. Blackshaw, M. M. Lai, I. A. Qureshi, A. F. Burnett, D. M. Sabatini and S. H. Snyder</A>
<J>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</J>
<V>95</V>
<P>8351-6.</P>
<Y>1998</Y>
<Ab><Entity id="21" Instanceof="20">p70 S6 kinase</Entity> (<Entity id="22" Acronym="21">p70(S6k)</Entity>) is a <Entity id="20" Type="Protein">mitogen-activated protein kinase</Entity> that plays a central role in the control of mRNA translation. <Entity id="23" Antecedent="21">It</Entity> physiologically <ComplexRelation id="25" Complexor="23"  Complexee="24" Kind="Undetermined">phosphorylates</ComplexRelation> the <Entity id="24" Type="Protein">S6 protein of the 40s ribosomal subunit</Entity> in response to mitogenic stimuli and is a downstream component of the rapamycin-sensitive pathway, which includes the 12-kDa <Entity id="26" Type="Protein">FK506 binding protein</Entity> and includes rapamycin and the 12-kDa FK506 binding protein target 1. Here, we report the identification of <Entity id="35" Instanceof="34">neurabin</Entity> (neural tissue-specific <Entity id="33" Type="Protein">F-actin binding protein</Entity>), <Entity id="34" Type="Protein">a neuronally enriched protein</Entity> of 1,095 amino acids that contains a PDZ domain and <ComplexRelation id="37" Complexor="34"  Complexee="36" Kind="Undetermined">binds</ComplexRelation> <Entity id="36" Type="Protein">p70(S6k)</Entity>. We demonstrate the <Entity id="38" Type="Protein">neurabin</Entity> <Entity id="39" Type="Protein">p70 (S6k)</Entity> <ComplexRelation id="40" Complexor="38"  Complexee="39" Kind="Undetermined">interaction</ComplexRelation> by yeast two-hybrid analysis and biochemical techniques. <Entity id="44" Type="Protein">p70(S6k)</Entity> and <Entity id="45" Type="Protein">neurabin</Entity> <ComplexRelation id="46" Complexor="44"  Complexee="45" Kind="Undetermined">coimmunoprecipitate</ComplexRelation> from transfected HEK293 cells. Site-directed mutagenesis of <Entity id="47" Type="Protein">neurabin</Entity> <ComplexRelation id="51" Complexor="49"  Complexee="50" Kind="Undetermined">implicates <Entity id="49" Type="Protein domain"><Entity id="48" Antecedent="47">its</Entity> PDZ domain</Entity> in the interaction with <Entity id="50" Type="Protein">p70(S6k)</Entity></ComplexRelation>, and deletion of the carboxyl-terminal five amino acids of p70(S6k) abrogates the interaction. Cotransfection of neurabin in HEK293 cells activates p70(S6k) kinase activity. The mRNA of neurabin and p70(S6k) show striking colocalization in brain sections by in situ hybridization. Subcellular fractionation of rat brain demonstrates that neurabin and p70(S6k) both localize to the soluble fraction of synaptosomes. By way of <Entity id="52" Type="Protein"><Entity id="51" Antecedent="50">its</Entity> PDZ domain</Entity>, the <Entity id="50" Type="Protein">neuronal-specific neurabin</Entity> may target p70(S6k) to nerve terminals.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>The leukemic protein core binding factor beta (CBFbeta)-smooth-muscle myosin heavy chain sequesters CBFalpha2 into cytoskeletal filaments and aggregates</T>
<A>N. Adya, T. Stacy, N. A. Speck and P. P. Liu</A>
<J>Mol Cell Biol</J>
<V>18</V>
<P>7432-43</P>
<Y>1998</Y>
<Ab><Entity id="43" Type="gene">The fusion gene CBFB-MYH11</Entity> is generated by the chromosome 16 inversion associated with acute myeloid leukemias. <Entity id="44" Antecedent="43">This gene</Entity> encodes a chimeric protein involving the <Entity id="1" Type="Protein">core binding factor beta</Entity> (<Entity id="2" Aliasof="1">CBFbeta</Entity>) and the <Entity id="3" Type="Protein">smooth-muscle myosin heavy chain</Entity> <Entity id="4" Aliasof="3">SMMHC</Entity>. Mouse model studies suggest that this <Entity id="45" Type="Protein">chimeric protein CBFbeta-SMMHC</Entity> dominantly <InhibitRelation id="47" Inhibitor="45"  Inhibitee="46" Kind="Undetermined">suppresses</InhibitRelation> the <Entity id="46" Type="Protein">function of CBF</Entity>, a heterodimeric transcription factor composed of DNA binding subunits (CBFalpha1 to 3) and a non-DNA binding subunit (CBFbeta). <Entity id="10" Antecedent="47">This dominant suppression</Entity>
 results in the blockage of hematopoiesis in mice and presumably contributes to leukemogenesis. We used transient-transfection assays, in combination with immunofluorescence and green fluorescent protein-tagged proteins, to monitor subcellular localization of CBFbeta-SMMHC, CBFbeta, and CBFalpha2 (also known as AML1 or PEBP2alphaB). When expressed individually, CBFalpha2 was located in the nuclei of transfected cells, whereas CBFbeta was distributed throughout the cell. On the other hand, CBFbeta-SMMHC formed filament-like structures that colocalized with actin filaments. Upon cotransfection, CBFalpha2 was able to drive localization of CBFbeta into the nucleus in a dose-dependent manner. In, CBFalpha2 colocalized with CBFbeta-SMMHC along the filaments instead of localizing to the nucleus. Deletion of the CBFalpha-interacting domain within CBFbeta-SMMHC abolished this CBFalpha2 sequestration, whereas truncation of the C-terminal-end SMMHC domain led to nuclear localization of CBFbeta-SMMHC when coexpressed with CBFalpha2. CBFalpha2 sequestration by CBFbeta-SMMHC was further confirmed in vivo in a knock-in mouse model. These observations suggest that CBFbeta-SMMHC plays a dominant negative role by sequestering CBFalpha2 into cytoskeletal filaments and aggregates, thereby disrupting CBFalpha2-mediated regulation of gene expression.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Modulation of chromatin structure regulates cytokine gene expression during T cell differentiation</T>
<A>S. Agarwal and A. Rao</A>
<J>Immunity</J>
<V>9</V>
<P>765-75</P>
<Y>1998</Y>
<Ab><Entity id="2" Type="cell type">Differentiating cells</Entity> undergo programmed alterations in <Entity id="4" Type="molecular process"><Entity id="3" Antecedent="2">their</Entity> patterns of gene expression</Entity>, which are often regulated by structural changes in chromatin. Here we demonstrate that T cell differentiation results in long-range <Entity id="5" Type="molecular process">changes in the chromatin structure</Entity> of effector cytokine genes, <Entity id="6" Antecedent="5">which</Entity>
 persist in resting Th1 and Th2 cells in the absence of further stimulation. Differentiation of naive T helper cells into mature Th2 cells is associated with chromatin remodeling of the IL-4 and IL-13 genes, whereas differentiation into Th1 cells evokes remodeling of the IFNgamma but not IL-4 or IL-13 genes. IL-4 locus remodeling is accompanied by demethylation and requires both antigen stimulation and STAT6 activation. We propose that chromatin remodeling of cytokine gene loci is functionally associated with productive T cell differentiation and may explain the coordinate regulation of Th2 cytokine genes.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Neural activity in the primate prefrontal cortex during associative learning [see comments]</T>
<A>W. F. Asaad, G. Rainer and E. K. Miller</A>
<J>Neuron</J>
<V>21</V>
<P>1399-407</P>
<Y>1998</Y>
<Ab>The <Entity id="11" Type="Protein">prefrontal </Entity>(<Entity id="12" Aliasof="11">PF</Entity>) cortex has been implicated in the remarkable <Entity id="7" Type="physiological process">ability of primates to form and rearrange arbitrary associations rapidly</Entity>. <Entity id="8" Antecedent="7">This ability</Entity> was studied in two monkeys, using a task that required them to learn to make specific saccades in response to particular cues and then repeatedly reverse these responses. We found that the activity of individual PF neurons represented both the cues and the associated responses, perhaps providing a neural substrate for their association. Furthermore, during learning, neural activity conveyed the direction of the animals^ impending responses progressively earlier within each successive trial. The final level of activity just before the response, however, was unaffected by learning. These results suggest a role for the PF cortex in learning arbitrary cue-response associations, an ability critical for complex behavior.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Artemin, a novel member of the GDNF ligand family, supports peripheral and central neurons and signals through the GFRalpha3-RET receptor complex</T>
<A>R. H. Baloh, M. G. Tansey, P. A. Lampe, T. J. Fahrner, H. Enomoto, K. S. Simburger, M. L. Leitner, T. Araki, E. M. Johnson, Jr. and J. Milbrandt</A>
<J>Neuron</J>
<V>21</V>
<P>1291-302</P>
<Y>1998</Y>
<Ab>The <Entity id="13" Type="Protein">glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor</Entity> (<Entity id="14" Aliasof="13">GDNF</Entity>) ligands (GDNF, <Entity id="15" Type="Protein">Neurturin </Entity>[<Entity id="16" Aliasof="15">NTN</Entity>], and <Entity id="17" Type="Protein">Persephin </Entity>[<Entity id="18" Aliasof="17">PSP</Entity>]) signal through a multicomponent receptor system composed of a high-affinity binding component (GFRalpha1-GFRalpha4) and a common signaling component (RET). Here, we report the identification of Artemin, a novel member of the GDNF family, and demonstrate that it is the ligand for the former orphan receptor GFRalpha3-RET. <Entity id="9" Type="Protein">Artemin</Entity> is a survival factor for sensory and sympathetic neurons in culture, and <Entity id="11" Type="molecular process"><Entity id="10" Antecedent="9">its</Entity> expression pattern</Entity> suggests that <Entity id="12" Antecedent="9">it</Entity> also influences these neurons in vivo. Artemin can also activate the GFRalpha1-RET complex and supports the survival of dopaminergic midbrain neurons in culture, indicating that like GDNF (GFRalpha1-RET) and NTN (GFRalpha2-RET), Artemin has a preferred receptor (GFRalpha3-RET) but that alternative receptor interactions also occur.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Drosophila ecdysone receptor mutations reveal functional differences among receptor isoforms</T>
<A>M. Bender, F. B. Imam, W. S. Talbot, B. Ganetzky and D. S. Hogness</A>
<J>Cell</J>
<V>91</V>
<P>777-88</P>
<Y>1997</Y>
<Ab>The steroid hormone ecdysone directs Drosophila metamorphosis via three heterodimeric receptors that differ according to which of three ecdysone receptor isoforms encoded by the EcR gene (EcR-A, EcR-B1, or EcR-B2) is activated by the orphan nuclear receptor USP. We have identified and molecularly mapped two classes of EcR mutations: those specific to EcR-B1 that uncouple metamorphosis, and embryonic-lethal mutations that map to common sequences encoding the DNA- and ligand-binding domains. In the <Entity id="13" Type="gland">larval salivary gland</Entity>, loss of EcR-B1 results in loss of activation of ecdysone-induced genes. Comparable transgenic expression of EcR-B1, EcR-B2, and EcR-A in <Entity id="14" Antecedent="13">these mutant glands</Entity> results, respectively, in full, partial, and no repair of that loss.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Role of the lateral mammillary nucleus in the rat head direction circuit: a combined single unit recording and lesion study [published erratum appears in Neuron 1999 Jan;22(1):199]</T>
<A>H. T. Blair, J. Cho and P. E. Sharp</A>
<J>Neuron</J>
<V>21</V>
<P>1387-97</P>
<Y>1998</Y>
<Ab>We recorded <Entity id="19" Type="Protein">head direction</Entity> (<Entity id="20" Aliasof="19">HD</Entity>) cells from the <Entity id="21" Type="Protein">lateral mammillary nucleus</Entity> (<Entity id="22" Aliasof="21">LMN</Entity>) and <Entity id="23" Type="Protein">anterior thalamus</Entity> (<Entity id="24" Aliasof="23">ATN</Entity>) of freely behaving rats and also made bilateral lesions of LMN while recording HD cells from ATN. We discovered that the tuning functions of LMN HD cells become narrower during contraversive head turns, but not ipsiversive head turns, compared to when the head is not turning. This narrowing effect does not occur for ATN HD cells. We also found that the HD signal in LMN leads that in ATN by about 15-20 ms. When LMN was lesioned bilaterally, <Entity id="15" Type="cell type">HD cells</Entity> in ATN immediately lost <Entity id="17" Type="physiological process"><Entity id="16" Antecedent="15">their</Entity> directional firing properties</Entity> and never recovered <Entity id="18" Antecedent="17">them</Entity>. Based on these findings, we argue that LMN may be an essential component of an attractor-integrator network that participates in generating the HD signal.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Inducible nonlymphoid expression of Fas ligand is responsible for superantigen-induced peripheral deletion of T cells</T>
<A>E. Bonfoco, P. M. Stuart, T. Brunner, T. Lin, T. S. Griffith, Y. Gao, H. Nakajima, P. A. Henkart, T. A. Ferguson and D. R. Green</A>
<J>Immunity</J>
<V>9</V>
<P>711-20</P>
<Y>1998</Y>
<Ab><Entity id="25" Type="Protein">Fas </Entity><Entity id="26" Aliasof="25">CD95</Entity> and <Entity id="27" Type="Protein">Fas ligand</Entity> <Entity id="28" Aliasof="27">FasL</Entity> play major roles in <Entity id="29" Type="Protein">staphylococcal enterotoxin B</Entity> <Entity id="30" Aliasof="29">SEB</Entity>-induced peripheral deletion of Vbeta8+ T cells. We found that peripheral deletion was defective in radiation chimeras with non-functional tissue FasL, regardless of the FasL status of the bone marrow-derived cells. SEB induced a <Entity id="19" Type="molecular process">upregulation of FasL</Entity>. <Entity id="20" Antecedent="19">This effect</Entity>
 was resistant to inhibition by cyclosporin A, which also failed to inhibit peripheral deletion. In SCID animals nonlymphoid tissues did not express FasL in response to SEB unless transplanted lymphocytes were present. Thus, some
 immune responses induce <Entity id="21" Type="Protein">FasL</Entity> in nonlymphoid tissues, <Entity id="22" Antecedent="21">which</Entity> in turn kills activated lymphocytes, leading to peripheral T cell deletion.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Regulation of PAK activation and the T cell cytoskeleton by the linker protein SLP-76</T>
<A>J. Bubeck Wardenburg, R. Pappu, J. Y. Bu, B. Mayer, J. Chernoff, D. Straus and A. C. Chan</A>
<J>Immunity</J>
<V>9</V>
<P>607-16</P>
<Y>1998</Y>
<Ab>Tyrosine phosphorylation of linker proteins enables the <Entity id="35" Type="Protein">T cell antigen receptor</Entity> (<Entity id="36" Aliasof="35">TCR</Entity>)-associated protein tyrosine kinases to phosphorylate and regulate effector molecules that generate second messengers. We demonstrate here that the <Entity id="23" Type="Protein">SLP-76 linker protein</Entity> <ComplexRelation id="29" Complexor="23"  Complexee="25, 27" Kind="Undetermined">interacts with both</ComplexRelation> <Entity id="25" Instanceof="24">nck</Entity>, an <Entity id="24" Type="Protein">adaptor protein</Entity>, and <Entity id="27" Instanceof="26">Vav</Entity>, a <Entity id="26" Type="Protein">guanine nucleotide exchange factor for Rho-family GTPases</Entity>. The assembly of <Entity id="28" Antecedent="23, 25, 27">this tri-molecular complex</Entity>
 permits the activated Rho-family GTPases to regulate target effectors that interact through nck. In turn, assembly of this complex mediates the enzymatic activation of the p21-activated protein kinase 1 and facilitates actin polymerization. Hence, phosphorylation of linker proteins not only bridges the TCR-associated PTK, ZAP-70, with downstream effector proteins, but also provides a scaffold to integrate distinct signaling complexes to regulate T cell function.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>An olfactory sensory map develops in the absence of normal projection neurons or GABAergic interneurons</T>
<A>A. Bulfone, F. Wang, R. Hevner, S. Anderson, T. Cutforth, S. Chen, J. Meneses, R. Pedersen, R. Axel and J. L. Rubenstein</A>
<J>Neuron</J>
<V>21</V>
<P>1273-82</P>
<Y>1998</Y>
<Ab>Olfactory sensory neurons expressing a given odorant receptor project to two <Entity id="30" Type="?">topographically fixed glomeruli in the olfactory bulb</Entity>. We have examined the contribution of different cell types in the olfactory bulb to the establishment of <Entity id="31" Antecedent="30">this topographic map</Entity>. Mice with a homozygous deficiency in Tbr-1 lack most projection neurons, whereas mice with a homozygous deficiency in Dlx-1 and Dlx-2 lack most GABAergic interneurons. Mice bearing a P2-IRES-tau-lacZ allele and deficient in either Tbr-1 or Dlx-1/Dlx-2 reveal the convergence of axons to one medial and one lateral site at positions analogous to those observed in wild-type mice. These observations suggest that the establishment of a topographic map is not dependent upon cues provided by, or synapse formation with, the major neuronal cell types in the olfactory bulb.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Regulation of cocaine reward by CREB</T>
<A>W. A. Carlezon, Jr., J. Thome, V. G. Olson, S. B. Lane-Ladd, E. S. Brodkin, N. Hiroi, R. S. Duman, R. L. Neve and E. J. Nestler</A>
<J>Science</J>
<V>282</V>
<P>2272-5</P>
<Y>1998</Y>
<Ab>Cocaine regulates the transcription factor <Entity id="47" Type="Protein">CREB </Entity>(<Entity id="48" Aliasof="47">adenosine 3^, 5'-monophosphate response element binding protein</Entity>) in <Entity id="32" Type="?">rat nucleus accumbens</Entity>, <Entity id="33" Aliasof="32">a brain region that is important for addiction</Entity>. Overexpression of CREB in <Entity id="34" Antecedent="33">this region</Entity> decreases the rewarding effects of cocaine and makes low doses of the drug aversive. Conversely, overexpression of a dominant-negative mutant CREB increases the rewarding effects of cocaine. Altered transcription of dynorphin likely contributes to these effects: Its expression is increased by overexpression of CREB and decreased by overexpression of mutant CREB. Moreover, <Entity id="35" Type="molecular process">blockade of kappa opioid receptors</Entity> (on <Entity id="36" Antecedent="35">which</Entity> dynorphin acts) antagonizes the negative effect of CREB on cocaine reward. These results identify an intracellular cascade-culminating in gene expression-through which exposure to cocaine modifies subsequent responsiveness to the drug.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Combinatorial signaling codes for the progressive determination of cell fates in the Drosophila embryonic mesoderm</T>
<A>A. Carmena, S. Gisselbrecht, J. Harrison, F. Jimenez and A. M. Michelson</A>
<J>Genes Dev</J>
<V>12</V>
<P>3910-22</P>
<Y>1998</Y>
<Ab>Mesodermal progenitors arise in the Drosophila embryo from discrete clusters of lethal of scute (l'sc)-expressing cells. Using both genetic loss-of-function and targeted ectopic expression approaches, we demonstrate here that individual progenitors are specified by the sequential deployment of unique combinations of intercellular signals. Initially, the intersection between the <Entity id="49" Type="Protein">Wingless </Entity>(<Entity id="50" Aliasof="49">Wg</Entity>) and <Entity id="51" Type="Protein">Decapentaplegic </Entity>(<Entity id="52" Aliasof="51">Dpp</Entity>) expression domains demarcate an ectodermal prepattern that is imprinted on the adjacent mesoderm in the form of a L'sc precluster. All mesodermal cells within this precluster are competent to respond to a subsequent instructive signal mediated by two <Entity id="53" Type="Protein">receptor tyrosine kinases</Entity> (<Entity id="54" Aliasof="53">RTKs</Entity>), the <Entity id="55" Type="Protein">Drosophila epidermal growth factor receptor</Entity> (<Entity id="56" Aliasof="55">DER</Entity>) and the <Entity id="57" Type="Protein">Heartless </Entity>(<Entity id="58" Aliasof="57">Htl</Entity>) fibroblast growth factor receptor. By monitoring the expression of the diphosphorylated form of <Entity id="59" Type="Protein">mitogen-associated protein kinase</Entity> (<Entity id="60" Aliasof="59">MAPK</Entity>), we found that <Entity id="37" Antecedent="54">these RTKs</Entity> are activated in small clusters of cells within the original competence domain. Each cluster represents an equivalence group because all members initially resemble progenitors in theirr expression of both L'sc and mesodermal identity genes. Thus, localized RTK activity induces the formation of mesodermal equivalence groups. The RTKs remain active in the single progenitor that emerges from each cluster under the subsequent inhibitory influence of the neurogenic genes. Moreover, DER and Htl are differentially involved in the specification of particular progenitors. We conclude that distinct cellular identity codes are generated by the combinatorial activities of Wg, Dpp, EGF, and FGF signals in the progressive determination of embryonic mesodermal cells.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Exocrine gland dysfunction in MC5-R-deficient mice: evidence for coordinated regulation of exocrine gland function by melanocortin peptides</T>
<A>W. Chen, M. A. Kelly, X. Opitz-Araya, R. E. Thomas, M. J. Low and R. D. Cone</A>
<J>Cell</J>
<V>91</V>
<P>789-98</P>
<Y>1997</Y>
<Ab>The effects of pituitary-derived melanocortin peptides are primarily attributed to ACTH-mediated adrenocortical glucocorticoid production. Identification of a widely distributed receptor for <Entity id="39" Type="Protein">ACTH/MSH peptides</Entity>, the <Entity id="61" Type="Protein">melanocortin-5 receptor</Entity> (<Entity id="62" Aliasof="61">MC5-R</Entity>), suggested non-steroidally mediated systemic effects of <Entity id="40" Antecedent="39">these peptides</Entity>. Targeted disruption of the MC5-R produced mice with a severe defect in water repulsion and thermoregulation due to decreased production of sebaceous lipids. High levels of MC5-R was found in multiple exocrine tissues, including Harderian, preputial, lacrimal, and sebaceous glands, and was also shown to be required for production and stress-regulated synthesis of porphyrins by the Harderian gland and ACTH/MSH-regulated protein secretion by the lacrimal gland. These data show a requirement for the MC5-R in multiple exocrine glands for the production of numerous products, indicative of a coordinated system for regulation of exocrine gland function by melanocortin peptides.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Semaphorin-neuropilin interactions underlying sympathetic axon responses to class III semaphorins</T>
<A>H. Chen, Z. He, A. Bagri and M. Tessier-Lavigne</A>
<J>Neuron</J>
<V>21</V>
<P>1283-90</P>
<Y>1998</Y>
<Ab>Neuropilin-1 and neuropilin-2 show specificity in binding to different <Entity id="41" Type="Protein">class III semaphorins</Entity>, including <Entity id="42" Instanceof="41">Sema III, Sema E, and Sema IV</Entity>, suggesting that the specificity of action of <Entity id="43" Antecedent="42">these semaphorins</Entity> is dictated by the complement of neuropilins expressed by responsive neurons. In support of this, we show that <Entity id="44" Type="cell type">sympathetic axons</Entity> coexpress neuropilin-1 and -2, that <Entity id="46" Type="molecular process"><Entity id="45" Antecedent="44">their</Entity> responses</Entity>
 to Sema III, Sema E, and Sema IV are affected in predicted ways by antibodies to neuropilin-1, and that neuropilin-1 and -2 can form homo- and heterooligomers through an interaction involving at least partly the neuropilin <Entity id="67" Type="Protein">MAM </Entity>(<Entity id="68" Aliasof="67">meprin, A5, mu</Entity>) domain. These results support the idea that in sympathetic axons, the Sema III signal is mediated predominantly by neuropilin-1 oligomers, the Sema IV signal by neuropilin-2 oligomers, and the Sema E signal by neuropilin-1 and -2, either as homo- or heterooligomers.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>An essential role for retinoid receptors RARbeta and RXRgamma in long-term potentiation and depression</T>
<A>M. Y. Chiang, D. Misner, G. Kempermann, T. Schikorski, V. Giguere, H. M. Sucov, F. H. Gage, C. F. Stevens and R. M. Evans</A>
<J>Neuron</J>
<V>21</V>
<P>1353-61</P>
<Y>1998</Y>
<Ab>Hippocampal <Entity id="69" Type="Protein">long-term potentiation</Entity> (<Entity id="70" Aliasof="69">LTP</Entity>) and <Entity id="71" Type="Protein">long-term depression</Entity> (<Entity id="72" Aliasof="71">LTD</Entity>) are the most widely studied forms of synaptic plasticity thought to underlie spatial learning and memory. We report here that <Entity id="47" Type="?">RARbeta deficiency in mice</Entity> virtually eliminates hippocampal CA1 LTP and LTD. <Entity id="48" Antecedent="47">It</Entity>
 also results in substantial performance deficits in spatial learning and memory tasks. Surprisingly, RXRgamma null mice exhibit a distinct phenotype in which LTD is lost whereas LTP is normal. Thus, while <Entity id="49" Type="Protein">retinoid receptors</Entity> contribute to both LTP and LTD, <Entity id="50" Antecedent="49">they</Entity> do so in different ways. These findings not only genetically uncouple LTP and LTD but also reveal a novel and unexpected role for vitamin A in higher cognitive functions.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Neurological illness in <Entity id="51" Type="?">transgenic mice</Entity> expressing a prion protein with an insertional mutation</T>
<A>R. Chiesa, P. Piccardo, B. Ghetti and D. A. Harris</A>
<J>Neuron</J>
<V>21</V>
<P>1339-51</P>
<Y>1998</Y>
<Ab>Familial prion diseases are caused by mutations in the gene encoding the <Entity id="73" Type="Protein">prion protein</Entity> (<Entity id="74" Aliasof="73">PrP</Entity>). We have produced <Entity id="52" Type="?">transgenic mice</Entity> that express the mouse homolog of a mutant human PrP containing a nine octapeptide insertion associated with prion dementia. <Entity id="53" Antecedent="52">These mice</Entity> exhibit a slowly progressive neurological disorder characterized clinically by ataxia and neuropathologically by cerebellar atrophy and granule cell loss, gliosis, and PrP deposition that is most prominent in the cerebellum and hippocampus. Mutant PrP molecules expressed in the brains of <Entity id="54" Antecedent="53">these mice</Entity> are resistant to digestion by low concentrations of proteinase K and display several other biochemical properties reminiscent of <Entity id="75" Type="Protein">PrP(Sc)</Entity>, the <Entity id="76" Aliasof="75">pathogenic isoform of PrP</Entity>. These results establish a new transgenic animal model of an inherited human prion disorder.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Formation and specification of ventral neuroblasts is controlled by vnd in Drosophila neurogenesis</T>
<A>H. Chu, C. Parras, K. White and F. Jimenez</A>
<J>Genes Dev</J>
<V>12</V>
<P>3613-24</P>
<Y>1998</Y>
<Ab>During Drosophila neural development, neuroblasts delaminate from
 the neuroectoderm of each hemisegment in a stereotypic orthogonal array of five rows and three columns (ventral, intermediate, and dorsal). Prevailing evidence indicates that the individual neuroblast fate is determined by the domain-specific expression of genes along the dorsoventral and anteroposterior axis. Here, we analyze the role of <Entity id="56" Instanceof="55">Vnd</Entity>, <Entity id="55" Type="Protein">a NK-2 homeodomain protein</Entity>, expressed initially in the ventral neuroectoderm adjacent to the ventral midline, in the dorsoventral patterning of the neuroectoderm and the neuroblasts. We show that in vnd null mutants most ventral neuroblasts do not form and the few that form do not develop ventral fates, but instead develop intermediate-like fates. Furthermore, we demonstrate that <Entity id="57" Type="Protein">Vnd</Entity> influences the gene expression patterns in the ventral proneural clusters and neuroectoderm, and that <Entity id="59" Type="molecular process"><Entity id="58" Type="57">its</Entity> action</Entity> in neuroblast formation includes, but is not exclusive to the activation of proneural AS-C genes. Through the use of GAL4/UAS gene-expression system we show that ectopic Vnd expression can promote ventral-like fates in intermediate and dorsal neuroblasts and can suppress certain normal characteristics of the intermediate and dorsal neuroectoderm. Our results are discussed in the context of the current evidence in dorsoventral patterning in the Drosophila neuroectoderm.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>A novel class of evolutionarily conserved genes defined by piwi are essential for stem cell self-renewal</T>
<A>D. N. Cox, A. Chao, J. Baker, L. Chang, D. Qiao and H. Lin</A>
<J>Genes Dev</J>
<V>12</V>
<P>3715-27</P>
<Y>1998</Y>
<Ab><Entity id="77" Type="Protein">Germ-line stem cells</Entity> (<Entity id="78" Aliasof="77">GSCs</Entity>) serve as the source for gametogenesis in diverse organisms. We cloned and characterized the <Entity id="60" Type="gene">Drosophila piwi gene</Entity> and showed that <Entity id="61" Antecedent="60">it</Entity> is required for the asymmetric division of GSCs to produce and maintain a daughter GSC but is not essential for the further differentiation of the committed daughter cell. Genetic mosaic and RNA in situ analyses suggest that piwi expression in adjacent somatic cells regulates GSC division. piwi encodes a highly basic novel protein, well conserved during evolution. We isolated piwi homologs in Caenorhabditis elegans and humans and also identified Arabidopsis piwi-like genes known to be required for meristem cell maintenance. Decreasing C. elegans piwi expression reduces the proliferation of GSC-equivalent cells. Thus, piwi represents a novel class of genes required for GSC division in diverse organisms.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Identification of the mouse neuromuscular degeneration gene and mapping of a second site suppressor allele</T>
<A>G. A. Cox, C. L. Mahaffey and W. N. Frankel</A>
<J>Neuron</J>
<V>21</V>
<P>1327-37</P>
<Y>1998</Y>
<Ab>The <Entity id="63" Type="gene">nmd mouse mutation</Entity> causes progressive degeneration of spinal motor neurons and muscle atrophy. We identified <Entity id="64" Antecedent="63">the mutated gene</Entity> as the putative <Entity id="79" Type="gene">transcriptional activator and ATPase/DNA helicase</Entity> previously described as <Entity id="80" Aliasof="79">Smbp2, Rip1, Gf1, or Catf1</Entity>. Mutations were found in two alleles-a single amino acid deletion in nmdJ and a splice donor mutation in nmd2J. The selective vulnerability of motor neurons is striking in view of the widespread expression of <Entity id="65" Antecedent="64">this gene</Entity>, although the pattern of degeneration may reflect a specific threshold since neither allele is null. In addition, the severity of the nmd phenotype is attenuated in a semidominant fashion by a major genetic locus on <Entity id="81" Type="Protein">chromosome </Entity>(<Entity id="82" Aliasof="81">Chr</Entity>) 13. The identification of the nmd gene and mapping of a major suppressor provide new opportunities for understanding mechanisms of motor neuron degeneration.</Ab>
</Article>
<Article>
<T>Identification of a class of <Entity id="66" Type="gene">chromatin boundary elements</Entity></T>
<A>O. Cuvier, C. M. Hart and U. K. Laemmli</A>
<J>Mol Cell Biol</J>
<V>18</V>
<P>7478-86</P>
<Y>1998</Y>
<Ab><Entity id="67" Antecedent="66">Boundary elements</Entity> are thought to define the ends of functionally independent domains of genetic activity. An assay for boundary activity based on this concept measures the ability to insulate a bracketed, chromosomally integrated reporter gene from position effects. Despite <Entity id="72" Antecedent="71">their</Entity>
 presumed importance, the few <Entity id="71" Antecedent="67">examples</Entity>
 identified to date apparently do not share sequence motifs or DNA binding proteins. The Drosophila protein BEAF binds the scs^ boundary element of the 87A7 hsp70 locus and roughly half of <Entity id="69" Type="gene">polytene chromosome interband loci</Entity>. To see if <Entity id="70" Antecedent="69">these sites</Entity> represent a class of boundary elements that have BEAF in common, we have isolated and studied several genomic BEAF binding sites as <Entity id="83" Type="Protein">candidate boundary elements</Entity> (<Entity id="84" Aliasof="83">cBEs</Entity>). BEAF binds with high affinity to clustered, variably arranged CGATA motifs present in these cBEs. No other sequence homologies were found. Two cBEs were tested and found to confer position-independent expression on a mini-white reporter gene in transgenic flies. Furthermore, point mutations in CGATA motifs that eliminate binding by BEAF also eliminate the ability to confer position-independent expression. Taken together, these findings suggest that clustered CGATA motifs are a hallmark of a BEAF-utilizing class of boundary elements found at many loci. This is the first example of a class of boundary elements that share a sequence motif and a binding protein.</Ab>
</Article>
</Articles>
